# Irene Smith

11 Brooklyn Street • Port Jervis, NY 12771 • 845-699-2258 irenesmith13@gmail.com • http://www.irenesmith.com • @Story\_Teller

## **Summary**

Hybrid developer/technical writer, with over 30 years' experience with multiple programming languages and technologies. Comfortable with full stack development of both native applications for Windows as well as website and web-based applications. Extensive experience writing API documentation, design and requirement documents, and release notes.

## **Technical Skills**

Windows Application Development: C# and VB.NET, VBA, Java, C, C++, Python

Web Development: HTML 5, CSS 3, JavaScript, jQuery, AngularJS, Bootstrap, ASP .NET, ASP 3.0

Database: Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL, Oracle, Microsoft Access, MongoDB

Graphics and Video: Adobe PhotoShop, Adobe Lightroom, PaintShop Pro, Gimp, Microsoft Visio,

Snaglt, OBS Studio, Adobe After Effects, Jingo

Source Control: Git, Perforce, Visual Source Safe (VSS), SVN, Team Foundation Server (TFS)

Writing Tools: Microsoft Office, Google Docs, RoboHelp, Scrivener, Open Office

Development Tools: Sublime Text 3, Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux (Ubuntu), DOS, macOS

## **Professional Experience**

#### Mozilla

Firefox Developer Content Manager On contract through **Harvey Nash**  6/2018 - 11/2019

#### Responsibilities

- Manage content for MDN Web Docs Browser Extensions and Firefox Developer Tools
- Write tutorials for web development
- Update and refine existing content to reflect new and updated Firefox features and web development best practices
- Create example code for tutorials and web APIs

#### **MongoDB**

**Technical Writer** 

9/2017 - 3/2018

Responsibilities

- Wrote documentation for MongoDB Atlas
- Collaborated with developers to document new features of MongoDB
- Created web documentation for MongoDB using restructured Text (reST) and Sphinx

## **Moody's Analytics**

Technical Writer

11/2016 - 6/2017

## On contract through Randstad Technologies

Responsibilities

- Worked with developers to create technical documentation for Cloud Computing Project
- Created stylesheets and documentation templates
- Helped define processes for support, development, and technical documentation projects
- Created quick guides, workflows, and high-level overviews for end users

#### Credit Suisse, New York, NY

Technical Writer
On contract through Insight Global

5/2016 - 9/2016

Resume of Irene Smith Page 2

## Responsibilities

- Interviewed Developers to create technical documentation for CCAR Application Modules
- Helped to create SAD (Software Architecture Documentation) document for CCAR Application
- Created data flow and architectural diagrams and application screenshots
- Wrote reference materials for use by support personnel in application troubleshooting

#### BNP Paribas, New York, NY

Developer

6/2015 - 12/2015

#### On contract through Huxley Associates

## Responsibilities

- Wrote C# console applications that are run as automated processes to update trade data
- Created VBA Scripts for Microsoft Excel that create reports for traders
- Enhanced the UI of a stock pricing application that uses MVC, Angular, and Bootstrap
- Wrote, reviewed, and edited project requirements and user stories

#### **TIAA-CREF, Charlotte, NC (Remote)**

Senior Technical Writer

11/2013 - 2/2015

## On contract through Stratus Technologies, LLC

## Responsibilities

- Create and maintain templates and VBA macros to simplify document creation
- Create and update the Developer's Reference for the PRISM API, an application that uses Oracle coherence to cache mainframe data for a Java API
- Create and update a data dictionary for use by PRISM developers
- Create and update walkthroughs for the PRISM application that include step-by-step instructions and screenshots

#### Google, Inc., New York, NY 10011

Technical Writer III, on one-year contract through **Apex Systems, Inc.** 

7/2012 -7/2013

#### Responsibilities

- Wrote technical guides and other documentation using HTML5, CSS3, and markdown
- Wrote and maintained API documentation for the following Ad Exchange technologies: Buyer REST API, Seller REST API, Buyer SOAP API, Real-time Bidding Protocol
- Wrote the developer's guide for Google's open source project, Open Bidder

## Medidata Solutions, Inc. New York, NY 10003

Senior Programming Technical Communicator Senior Technical Communicator, **Team Lead** Technical Communicator 1/2010 - 1/2012 1/2008 - 1/2010

#### 9/2006 - 1/2008

## Responsibilities

- Scrum Master for internal tools for the Technical Communications department
- Used C# to develop ASP .NET applications, Windows applications, and Microsoft Word add-ins. These tools reduced document preparation time from days to minutes
- Used SQL Server to design and create database model for all internal tools including table design, stored procedures and functions
- · Lead and mentored colleagues in creating design specifications
- Team Lead for multiple documentation projects
- Created and presented internal training for new team members

#### Times Herald Record, Middletown, NY 10940

Paginator, Assistant Obituary Editor

2/2005 - 1/2006

#### Responsibilities

• Developed a set of Microsoft Word macros to automate the process preparing obituaries, thus reducing preparation time from over half an hour to less than one minute

Resume of Irene Smith Page 3

- Documented obituary and classified preparation procedures
- Prepared obituaries and classified advertising for printing

#### Microsoft, Redmond, WA 98052

Programming Writer (FTE), SQL Server Group

4/2000 - 10/2003

## Responsibilities

- Developed samples for the System. Data namespace of the .NET Framework for versions 1.0,
   1.1, and 2.0 using C# and VB .NET to create console and ASP .NET applications
- Used C++, Visual Basic 6.0, Java (Microsoft J++), JavaScript, and VBScript to develop console application examples for Microsoft ADO, OLE DB, and ODBC API references
- Developed examples for Microsoft XML using C++ and Visual Basic

#### mpl2.com, Bellevue, WA

Programming Writer (on contract at Microsoft)

8/1999 - 3/2000

Originally called Meridian Partners, Ltd., mpl2.com placed writers in contract positions at various locations in Redmond, Bellevue, and Seattle including Microsoft.

#### Responsibilities

- Wrote conceptual and API reference documentation for Microsoft's database objects
- Used C++, Jscript, Visual Basic 6.0, VBScript, and Java to develop ASP 3.0 and console example applications for Microsoft ADO, OLE DB, and ODBC API references

## CRS, Newburgh, NY

**Application Developer** 

4/1998 - 8/1999

#### Responsibilities

- Developed and maintained all modules in the Point of Sale suite
- Designed and developed a data warehousing application that rolls up sales data on a daily basis for retail customers

#### **Solo Game Development**

Designed, coded, created graphics, and wrote context-sensitive help files for several Microsoft Windows commercial game packages:

- Casino Nights (Craps, Roulette, Black Jack, and Video Poker)
- **Dice Games** (Crag, Over 'n Under, and Bird Cage)
- Solitaire (Pyramid and Golf)

#### **Education**

University of Phoenix, Online

BS Information Technology/Software Design. GPA 3.92

**S.U. N.Y New Paltz**, New Paltz, NY 15 Credits **GPA 3.4** 

Orange County Community College, Middletown, NY AA, Liberal Arts GPA 3.38